<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>anxiety on The Skreegs</title>
    <link>https://www.scorch.org/tags/anxiety/</link>
    <description>Recent content in anxiety on The Skreegs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2017 Foo Bar</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.scorch.org/tags/anxiety/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Monster Between The Cracks</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/monster-between-the-cracks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/monster-between-the-cracks/</guid>
      <description>The process of switching from one SRRI to another is quite simple. You cut down a bit on the one you&amp;rsquo;re taking for a few days then switch over to the other, ramping up over the next couple of weeks. This process can be quite unpleasant however, the very reason you&amp;rsquo;re doing it is because you&amp;rsquo;re having quite an unpleasant time anyway. So it should just be a case of riding it out till the your new favourite drug kicks in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Fire</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/onfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/onfire/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been an anxiety sufferer for nearly 2 decades. The worst of which have been the last 3 months. Imagine every nerve in your body activated, ready to spring into action, heart speeded up, an increased sensitivity to everything happening in you body. Imagine being in this state from waking to bedtime, then all day the next day, the day after that. That&amp;rsquo;s how I currently live.
My condition has taken different shapes over the years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Todos &amp; Emerging from the Fog</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/todos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/todos/</guid>
      <description>I suffer from General Anxiety Disorder and the last few months have been a downhill spiral with the last few weeks being the worst I&amp;rsquo;ve ever experienced due to a switch of SRRI&amp;rsquo;s. In the evening&amp;rsquo;s I&amp;quot;ve been utterly unable to contribute to any project beyond the slightest triviality. This week however, the new drugs are kicking in and I&amp;rsquo;m feeling up. Time to get back on the horse and get stuff done.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>