<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miniskreeg on The Skreegs</title>
    <link>https://www.scorch.org/tags/miniskreeg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Miniskreeg on The Skreegs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2017 Foo Bar</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.scorch.org/tags/miniskreeg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I love wood with wood on it</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/i-love-wood-with-wood-on-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/i-love-wood-with-wood-on-it/</guid>
      <description>Trainset by Toys&amp;rsquo;r&amp;rsquo;Us. Table by Ozzy. After the Thomas Tank engine exhibition at the Ipswich railway museum I realised we needed a table quicksmart so I got stuck into it. What we have here is a mitred frame surrounded by a larger mitred frame to provide a lip and facia. The legs are fixed to both the frame and facia with gold coloured bolts. The table top is standard 15x600x900mm MDF which is double sided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toybox complete</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/toybox-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/toybox-complete/</guid>
      <description>Actually its been complete for a while but I&amp;rsquo;m just slow at getting pictures online. It&amp;rsquo;s turned out great for something made out of scrap wood by an IT bloke who knows nothing about wood (I love wood). Everything a toddler could ask for. Nice bright paint, heavy duty varnish and a chain to trap the fingers when gravity and the lid conspire against him (again).
{% img /static/images/img_2830.jpg 640 %}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&gt;Miniskreeg walks!</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/miniskreeg-walks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/miniskreeg-walks/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;Well he took his time getting around to it but at 1 year and 2 days little Miniskreeg finally decided to start walking on his own. It&amp;rsquo;s like a switch has just turned on enabling him to do it. Amazingly, we caught it on video as well. Here we go.
http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=1722270&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1
I&amp;rsquo;m trying out Vimeo instead of youtube this time as I hear the quality is better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&gt;Cooper vids</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/cooper-vids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/cooper-vids/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;A whole buncha new Miniskreeg vids courtesy of glootube. He&amp;rsquo;s 8.5 months now and crawling, laughin, grabbing, screamin, falling, hurting, laughing, crawling, crawling and crawling. Did I say he could crawl?
http://www.youtube.com/p/0FB67FE2B571AED8
There&amp;rsquo;s 6 videos in all. You click on the little grey bits left and right to change between them. If thats too hard you can go here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&gt;7 months on</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/7-months-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/7-months-on/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;Hard to believe Cooper is 7 months old now. When I look at him now its very hard to remember the little baby he used to be. He&amp;rsquo;s changed so much and is more a little boy now than a baby. He&amp;rsquo;s still got the cold and has done ever since he started daycare. Toblerones are few and far between as well which makes us worry slightly about another relapse into compact bowel mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&gt;Coopermergency</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/coopermergency/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/coopermergency/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;Lille Cooperman was rushed into the hozzie last friday morning. Some violent vomiting followed by going limp and extremely white prompted us to get an ambulance pronto. 3 hours and an ultrasound later confirmed it as an&amp;hellip;. wait for it&amp;hellip;.. intersusection of the bowel. Yeah I know, wtf is that you say? Its when the bowel, not being the brightest organ in the trunk decides to push itself into itself telescopic style.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&gt;A finer cog count on the sprocket of time.</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/a-finer-cog-count-on-the-sprocket-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/a-finer-cog-count-on-the-sprocket-of-time/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;Time these days is weird. Time used to work like this. You would do stuff, then do more stuff, then even more stuff then say something like &amp;ldquo;geez where has the last year went&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;remember that stuff we done? That was five years ago what happened?&amp;quot;. This is because in general every day terms not a lot changes that fast. You age so slowly you don&amp;rsquo;t notice it until you try and do Kung Fu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&gt;God is weird</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/god-is-weird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/god-is-weird/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;After the emergence of Sprogzilla I&amp;rsquo;ve gave a bit of thought towards Intelligent Design. The extremes of the birthing process, from the pain of delivery to the love of the result, seems too freakish to be the product of just random evolution.
Another factor lending credence to this theory is one of limbs. We&amp;rsquo;ve discovered that the average parent requires a minimum of three arms to successfully administer to the needs of a baby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooper James Hamilton. The Birth.</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/cooper-james-hamilton-the-birth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/cooper-james-hamilton-the-birth/</guid>
      <description>Cooper James Hamilton was born on 11/09/2007 at 18.10 weighing 8lbs 9oz and this is his story.
Monday 5am
Mum jumps out of bed having felt her waters break. Excitement takes hold, we phone the hospital and they tell us to come in. We, probably naively, phone relatives and we get into the hospital at about 7am. An examination ensues and membranes are still present over the babies head. Waters can break up behind the babies head but though they can&amp;rsquo;t confirm this they treat it like it&amp;rsquo;s broken anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&gt;Double Ding</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/double-ding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/double-ding/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;Due date today. Last 24 hours Hazel&amp;rsquo;s been having slight painful contractions randomly between 14 and 30 minutes. Still can&amp;rsquo;t be called the start of labour but it does make me think somethings gonna happen in the next couple of days. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a guess at a hospital visit Monday morning. Let&amp;rsquo;s say I have to go to work on Monday morning then have to come home again as soon as I get there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&gt;Ding! Time&#39;s up</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/ding-times-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/ding-times-up/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;Yay! Today the bell finally when on the Oven of Sprogzilla. MiniSkreeg is now 37 weeks and full term. Come out and tidy your room! We&amp;rsquo;re basically just waiting now. Everything is prepared, room ready, little socks ironed, hospital bags packed. All we need now is a good ol&amp;rsquo; flex of the uterus.
I suppose I should write something about how I feel coming up to this life changing event but I find the gestation process, and the preparation work you do during it has taken so long that it&amp;rsquo;s kinda taken away some of the impact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Miniskreeg</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/introducing-miniskreeg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/introducing-miniskreeg/</guid>
      <description>The 13 week scan was over a month ago now but no less a significant event now than it was then. I&amp;rsquo;ve always looked at pictures of other peoples scans with almost complete disinterest. A static photo just simply doesn&amp;rsquo;t do the event justice. The image is basically a real time &amp;ldquo;slice&amp;rdquo; of the baby and surrounding paraphernalia. Each frame taken by itself looks like a mess but with the doctor moving the &amp;ldquo;camera&amp;rdquo; back and forth the image constantly changes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>