<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>4wd on The Skreegs</title>
    <link>https://www.scorch.org/tags/4wd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 4wd on The Skreegs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2017 Foo Bar</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.scorch.org/tags/4wd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sorry Mr Bank Manager...</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/sorry-mr-bank-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/sorry-mr-bank-manager/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip;but I had to do it. While I have cash in the bank I decided to buy another car. We&amp;rsquo;ve up/downgraded to a 1999 Pajero (Shogun to old world folks). Its got real low mileage and its real clean for an 8 year old car. It does however, have a heart breaking 3.5ltr petrol donk in it. The reasoning is that in order to go camping we need more space. Baby + Car seat + Camping gear does not in any way equal a Grande Vitara so it has to go and I owe nature a slice of my soul when I die.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&gt;Glasshouse Mountains</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/glasshouse-mountains/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/glasshouse-mountains/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;Oh the joy of a non-updated blog.
While the outlaws were visiting over July time I exploited the presence of 2 larger males in the group as a reason to wheeling. We met up with a ragtag log from the Outerlimits4x4 forum and off we went into the bush at the Glasshouse Mountains. This is an area the zook club go to quite often but somehow I&amp;rsquo;ve never got there. The trouble with going with the Outerlimits crew is since it&amp;rsquo;s not an official club the trip is lacking a certain feeling of safety and responsibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beast Carnage</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/beast-carnage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/beast-carnage/</guid>
      <description>Gran and Grandpa Skreeg were over visiting during the last month. I thought it would be nice to take Grandpa Skreeg out &amp;ldquo;wheeling&amp;rdquo; in The Beast[tm], a 1992 Suzuki Sierra. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much stock with only a body lift and 29&amp;rdquo; tyres on it but I love it to bits. It&amp;rsquo;s good fun. Anyway, ol Papa Skreeg used to do a bit of rally driving in his younger years and spent most of life hotting up cars in some form or another so you&amp;rsquo;d think he would be able to pick a line in a 4wd travelling at less than walking speed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>