<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blather on The Skreegs</title>
    <link>https://www.scorch.org/tags/blather/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blather on The Skreegs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2017 Foo Bar</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.scorch.org/tags/blather/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kung Fu Return</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/kung-fu-return/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/kung-fu-return/</guid>
      <description>I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write this down so I don&amp;rsquo;t forget when it happened. After a lapse of nearly 2 1/2 years which has seen me visit various specialists, had numerous scans and a double hip arthroscope, I returned to Kung Fu training last night. The session went well but I expected the worst today since I did have quite sore hip joints. Today though I only have normal muscle soreness from training and no joint pain whatsoever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&gt;Skreegles</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/skreegles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/skreegles/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;A brief update of what can be described in business speak as &amp;ldquo;where we&amp;rsquo;re at and what we look like going forward&amp;rdquo;.
HousePainters are finishing off the outside next week. The project is then complete with only the inside to be finished. We&amp;rsquo;re trying to get that done quick smart as Coop is almost needing somewhere to stretch his legs.
CarsDisaster: The Beast has a busted gearbox. No idea whats wrong but its going to involve dropping the box out the thing and taking a look at whats most likely pieces of shrapnel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&gt;Blather #1</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/blather-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/blather-1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s an oddly grey day and apparently its supposed to rain all week. We get so used to Brisbane weather with its clear blue skies and comfortable temperatures during the non-summer months that its actually surprising and a little perplexing when its overcast. Its just so unusual to see.
I&amp;rsquo;m off ill yesterday and today with what is an excellent effort by Cooper to kill off his dad with exotic diseases from daycare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Press Play On Tape</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/more-press-play-on-tape/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/more-press-play-on-tape/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rate My Egg</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/rate-my-egg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/rate-my-egg/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s Happy Zombie Jesus weekend and we&amp;rsquo;ve done our eggs. Which one is best? The loser gets rolled a lot faster than a mortal ovum can survive.
Judge Egg.
[]: http://bp0.blogger.com/_MKqlq3WVEmY/RhiG9TnBYbI/AAAAAAAAAAk/aHwu-Chrhvg/s320/00020.jpg [![][]]: http://bp0.blogger.com/_MKqlq3WVEmY/RhiG9TnBYbI/AAAAAAAAAAk/aHwu-Chrhvg/s1600-h/00020.jpg [1]: http://bp3.blogger.com/_MKqlq3WVEmY/RhiHUDnBYcI/AAAAAAAAAAs/2nPVKdJe5lI/s320/00021.jpg [![][1]]: http://bp3.blogger.com/_MKqlq3WVEmY/RhiHUDnBYcI/AAAAAAAAAAs/2nPVKdJe5lI/s1600-h/00021.jpg</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to The Skreegs online!</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/welcome-to-the-skreegs-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/welcome-to-the-skreegs-online/</guid>
      <description>It seems this internet thing is quite popular and I see lots of people like to write blog thingies about their lives so other folk can see how much more dull there&amp;rsquo;s is in comparison. In an effort to make ours less dull I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start writing a blog thingy myself. Hey, I&amp;rsquo;ve only written a couple of sentences and I can feel my life becoming more interesting already. It really works!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>