<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freedom Cottage on The Skreegs</title>
    <link>https://www.scorch.org/tags/freedom-cottage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Freedom Cottage on The Skreegs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2017 Foo Bar</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.scorch.org/tags/freedom-cottage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Woah there slow down!</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/woah-there-slow-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/woah-there-slow-down/</guid>
      <description>7 days of builders doing stuff so far and they&amp;rsquo;ve done a hella lot. Amazing what you can do when someones giving you money to do it. Stuff done so far? Deck ripped up, sealed and nearly tiled, new concrete slab down underneath, round side and behind carport for the tank. Posts and cross timbers in for car port. Frame up for walls and back extension. There&amp;rsquo;s stuff just everywhere. Its like some mad builders construction bomb has went off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I love wood...</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/i-love-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/i-love-wood/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip; and just look at how much of it I&amp;rsquo;ve bought.
Yep, a little over a year and 2 months after getting plans drawn up we&amp;rsquo;ve finally got movement on the Kitten Ranch Expansion Project (KREP). We&amp;rsquo;ve got wood, steel beams, some concrete sheeting and a big feck off rusty builders trailer full of hidden secrets and black mojo. Rumour has it there&amp;rsquo;s some builders showing up at some point tomorrow to start dismantling the rear deck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&gt;Reno fun.</title>
      <link>https://www.scorch.org/archives/reno-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.scorch.org/archives/reno-fun/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve finally, nine months after getting plans drawn up, engaged a builder to start the extension of Freedom Cottage. However, 2 months in and engaged is all we&amp;rsquo;ve managed to do. Windows and steel is ordered but there&amp;rsquo;s some trouble with the concrete slab underneath. The council here demand thousands of dollars if you want to change your curtains and the certifier wants proof the slab underneath if cool. This is a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>